到目前为止，我们构建了一个很好的小节点 JS 应用程序。
So so far, we've built a nice
little Node.JS application.
它是在 Debian 上运行的
It's been running on Debian,
which is a perfectly valid and
完美的操作系统
perfectly great operating system.
有很多理由让你在 Debian里做点什么
There's lots of reasons that you
would run something inside of Debian.
但有一个问题是， Debian 相当大。
But there's an issue with the fact
that Debian is quite large.
这个节点包，我想，它的结尾几乎是一个千兆字节之类的东西。
This Node package, I think, ends up being
almost a gigabyte, something like that.
挺大的吧
It's quite large, right?
基本上，它是一个完整的操作系统，至少是它的文件结构。
It's a whole operating system basically,
at least the file structure for it.
如果我们能做点小的事情就太好了吧
So it'd be great if we could
make something smaller, right?
我想给大家介绍一下叫做 Alpine Linux的东西。
So I wanna introduce you to
something called Alpine Linux.
我们其实已经不小心使用了
It's something that we've actually kind
of already accidentally been using
因为很多东西都建在 Alpine 的 Linux 里
because a lot of things
are built in Alpine Linux, but
让我们先谈一下吧
let's go ahead and
just have a little chat about it.
所以 Alpine Linux 是最裸露的骨骼
So Alpine Linux is the most bare bones,
它可能是最小的 Linux 发行版。
smallest distribution of Linux
that it can possibly be.
它只包括它认为你需要运行你的
And it includes just the tools that it
thinks that you're gonna need to run your
毫无实际意义
application and literally nothing.
其他的都是你自己放的对吧
Everything else you have
to put in yourself, right?
优点是你从 900 兆字节到 5
The advantage is,
is you go from 900 megabytes to 5, so
阿尔卑斯的基本层为 5 兆字节。
Alpine's base layer is 5 megabytes.
其实你也知道
And actually just so you know,
Alpine 实际上是基于另一个叫做 BusyBox的 Linux 发行。
Alpine is actually based on another
distribution of Linux called BusyBox.
而我相信来自三星的 BusyBox 也许想让我看看这个
And BusyBox I believe came out of Samsung,
may want to look me up on that one.
但 BusyBox 有两兆字节甚至更多的尸骨
But BusyBox is two megabytes,
and it's even more bare bones,
我建议和 Alpine一起去
I would suggest just going with Alpine.
这些额外的 3 兆字节几乎都是你需要的东西。
Those extra three megabytes are almost
all things that you would need anyway.
所以你还是会重新安装这些东西的
So you would end up
reinstalling that stuff anyway.
在这里与 Alpine Linux 的交易是
The tradeoff here with
Alpine Linux is that
需要更多的工作才能弄点东西对吧
it just requires a lot more work
to get stuff working, right?
它甚至不包括认证中心。
It doesn't even include
certificate authorities.
不包括一堆你可能需要的东西
It doesn't include a bunch of stuff
that you would likely need, but
好消息是它没有你不需要的东西
the good news is,
it includes nothing that you don't need.
一个伟大的例子就是如果你包括德比
A great example of this is
like if you include Debian,
缺省情况下， Debian 为 Python。
on Debian by default is Python.
这是一种伟大的语言。
It's a great language.
我们在应用程序中完全没有使用 Python 。
We did not use Python at
all in our application.
所以这实际上是一个安全漏洞。
So it's actually a security vulnerability.
因此，如果某人可以进入我们的服务器并下载 Python 文件，那么他们可以
So if someone can get onto our server and
download a Python file, they can
和服务器上的 Python 解释器一起执行，对吧 ?
execute it right away with the Python
interpreter that's on the server, right?
但如果没有 Python 翻译，他们就得找到办法安装它，
But if there's no Python interpreter,
they'd have to find a way to install it,
这比连接到服务器要困难得多
and that's a lot more difficult
than just connecting to a server.
这就是 Alpine Linux 安全的原因
So that's why Alpine Linux is secure,
只要少些东西就安全了对吧
it's secure by just having
less stuff on it, right?
您只需要消除一系列的安全漏洞。
You just eliminate a whole class of
security vulnerabilities that you'll have.
另一种是，下载速度更快，存储成本更低，
The other thing is, things that download
a lot quicker, they're cheaper to store,
他们跑得更便宜
they're cheaper to run.
我不认为这是其中最大的部分
I don't necessarily think that's
the biggest part of this,
也许定价权，因为我知道 Azure 容器注册表，
maybe the pricing rights, because I know
things like Azure Container Registry,
它是容器的专用注册表，按大小进行收费。
which is a private registry for
containers, does charge by size.
所以你会在这方面节省一点钱
So you'll save yourself a little
bit of money in that respect,
但这不多对吧
but it's not much, right?
所以那是一个好的副作用，安全的部分其实是我认为的
So that's a nice side effect, the security
part is actually what I think is
使用较小版本的 Linux 的令人信服的原因。
the compelling reason to use
a smaller version of Linux.
那么，将你的项目从 Stretch 转至 Alpine 是多么困难 ?
So how hard is it to switch your
project from Stretch to Alpine?
好吧我们先打个球吧
Well, let's go give it a shot.
所以我要做的因为我很懒我不想重启
So what I'm gonna do, because I'm lazy and
I don't wanna restart
我的整个计划就是把所有东西都给我
my entire project,
is I'm gonna say cp- r everything in.
其实我要用 cd 的方法去把它说出来
Actually I'm gonna cd out of this and I'm
gonna say cp- r, more-complicated that,
我要把它放到一个叫阿尔卑斯 - linux的目录里
and I'm going to put that into
a directory called alpine-linux.
现在我有另一个叫 alpine-linux 的目录
So now I have another directory
called alpine-linux and
我把所有东西都抄过去了
I just copied everything over there.
我这样做，希望你可以回去参考你后来建的东西。
I'm doing this so hopefully you can go
back and reference what you built later.
就像你想象的一样，这里的一切都是一样的
So inside of here, as you may imagine,
everything's literally the same,
但我想把这个项目从 Debian 项目改为 Alpine 项目
but I wanna change this from Debian
project to a Alpine project.
还有一点你要做的巫术
And there's a bit of witchcraft
that you have to do,
你得把这个词改为高山
you have to change the word
stretch to alpine.
这就是你要做的一切
That's it, that's all you have to do.
那么现在如果我们回到这里说，我是在正确的目录里吗 ?
So now if we go back in here and
say, am I in the right directory?
我不是我要去高山 - linux
I'm not, I have to go into alpine-linux.
我们要重新开始工作
We're going to run build again, and again,
如果你想的话你可以给所有这些都有不同的标签
you could put different tags
on all these if you wanted to.
我不会去的
I'm not going to.
你可以看到有更多的层。
So you can see there's
a couple more layers.
我觉得节点一加节点到它大概是二十兆字节左右，
I think the Node one, once you add Node
into it, ends up being about 20 megabytes,
对， cuz 有一些工具可以和节点和 NPM 一起使用
right, cuz there's some tools that
come around with Node and NPM and
都是那种东西
all that kind of stuff.
再加上一堆节点模块，它们也会占用空间。
Plus you're gonna include a bunch of Node
modules, they'll take up space as well.
我想都是这么说的，我之前测量过这个，
I think all said and done,
I measured this earlier, and
我相信我们刚刚建造的这个集装箱是 80 兆字节，
I believe this container that we just
built I believe is 80 megabytes,
而不是 913 ，我觉得是我测量的另一个。
as opposed to 913,
I think is what I measured the other one.
所以是 913 到 86
So yeah, 913 to 86.
如果我们去码头检查我的程序
And if we just go to
docker inspect my-app.
在这里它会告诉你它有多大，大小，就在那里。
Somewhere in here it will tell you
how big it is, size, right there.
所以你得去计算出多少字节。
So you'd have to go and calculate
how many bytes that translates into.
根据我的资料，那是 86 兆字节。
According to my documentation here,
that's 86 megabytes.
好了，现在，如果我们继续，再试一次。
All right, so now if we go ahead and
try and run this again.
就在那儿就在那儿
Right there, right there, right there.
没问题的
Works just fine.
但我们现在要去阿尔卑斯而不是 Debian
But instead of using Debian,
we're now on to Alpine, but
我们只是用更少的方法挽救了整个一类的虫子
we just saved ourself an entire class
of bugs by including much less.
现在有一个 Debian 的分发
Now, there is a Debian distribution called
Debian SliM 如果我去了 12 人
Debian SLiM, so if I went 12-stretch-slim,
我认为你会下降到大约 150 兆字节，但是你仍然会得到完全的 Debian。
I think you go down to about 150
megabytes, but you still get full Debian.
这也是一种可能性。
So that's a possibility as well.
我知道很多人都这么做 Ubuntu 也这么做
I know lots of people do that,
Ubuntu used to do that as well,
有 Ubuntu 苗条，现在还没有完全 Ubuntu。
that there was Ubuntu slim and
now actually there is no full Ubuntu.
只是 Ubuntu 瘦了还有其他的要做的
It's just Ubuntu slim and everything
else you have to build yourself.
可能有一个完整的地方但我不知道怎么弄
There might be a full one somewhere,
but I don't know how to get it,
但这不重要
cuz it doesn't matter.
太好了
So, pretty good.
嗯，节点最新，上次我看的是 908 兆字节。
Yeah, node latest,
last time I checked was 908 megabytes.
而节点:12-alpine 大约为 80。
Whereas node:12-alpine is about 80.
很明显的区别
Pretty stark difference.
这就是我想谈谈 Linux 发行版的地方。
So this is kind of where I wanted to talk
a little bit about distributions of Linux.
第一，我不是 Linux 大师，任何想象力都是一样的。
One, I'm not a Linux master by
any stretch of the imagination.
当我使用 Linux 时，我就会使用 Ubuntu ，因为这就是我所了解的。
When I use Linux, I use Ubuntu just
because that's the one I know.
这是我一直用的
That's the one I've always used.
有些代理，我知道 Debian ，因为 Ubuntu 是基于 Debian的，对吧 ?
By some proxy, I know a bit about Debian
because Ubuntu is based on Debian, right?
所以我的默认是我用 Ubuntu 或 Debian 来做任何我在本地做的事情。
So my default is I use Ubuntu or Debian
for anything that I'm doing locally.
它有我知道如何使用的所有工具。
It has all the tools I know how to use.
当我把东西送到生产的时候
And then any time that I'm sending
stuff out to production, I try and
把它弄上阿尔派恩
get it on Alpine.
因为那是更小的，对的，更安全。
Because then it's smaller,
right, and more secure.
但是您完全可以使用 RHEL， Red Hat Enterprise Linux，
But you can totally do things with RHEL,
Red Hat Enterprise Linux,
这是另一个伟大的 Linux 发行版
that's another great
distribution of Linux Mint.
SUSE， Kali，它们都是 Linux的好分布。
SUSE, Kali,
they're all good distributions of Linux.
我最后想提的关于阿尔派恩的事
The last thing I wanted
to mention about Alpine.
所以它甚至不包括巴什。
So it doesn't even include bash.
这可能是我最难做的事，因为我必须这样做。
That's probably the hardest part about
this for me is that I have to do -it.
有一堆东西在用叫灰的东西
There's a bunch of stuff that,
it's using something called ash,
A-S-H 而不是 bash，它是一个最小的外壳和
A-S-H instead of bash,
which is a minimalistic shell and
不是一个满满的空壳是什么巴什是吧
not a full born-again shell,
which is what bash is, right?
所以是有区别的，我不认识，对吧 ?
So there are differences and
I don't know them, right?
所以，对于我来说，我并不是一直使用 Alpine 的原因之一
So that, for me, is one of the reasons
that I don't use Alpine all the time is
因为我不太了解阿什
because I don't know Ash very well.
那是我最后想说的
That was the last thing
I wanted to mention.